<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://gregoriomarchesini.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://gregoriomarchesini.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-06-14T21:00:12+00:00</updated><id>https://gregoriomarchesini.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">When acting is a legacy for future generations</title><link href="https://gregoriomarchesini.github.io/blog/2025/movies-clips/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When acting is a legacy for future generations"/><published>2025-06-06T16:40:16+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-06T16:40:16+00:00</updated><id>https://gregoriomarchesini.github.io/blog/2025/movies-clips</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gregoriomarchesini.github.io/blog/2025/movies-clips/"><![CDATA[<p>Among the actors that I love the most, there is one man that really changed my life in many aspects …</p> <blockquote> <p><strong>Robin Williams</strong> <br/> 1951 - 2014</p> </blockquote> <p>Apart from being a terrific and versatile actor with the ability to capture dramatic and joyful charaters with equal elegance, he was also a man trubled by drugs addition for parts of his life. He never once hidden his problems and he was very outspoken on the problems drugs addiction caused him.</p> <p>The first movie that I watched with him being the main character was probably <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jumanji">Jumanji</a>, which was cetainly a great deal of fun. But the first time I really saw this actor pushing the limit was in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dead_Poets_Society">Dead Poets Society</a>.</p> <p>While we are all told that our time on this planet is limited, I figured that only a handful of time it happened to me to deeply think about it. This clip certainly gave me one of these moments…</p> <h3 id="you-tube-clip">You Tube clip</h3> <p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vi0Lbjs5ECI"><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/vi0Lbjs5ECI/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Watch the video"/></a></p> <p>But this movie did not stop to surprise me here… in a moment in which I was also struggling with finding some relevance in putting efforts into performing well in school, in sport and in trying to find a way on what to do next in life. This click made me realize it was all about “contibuting a verse” to this life in which we all play some role. For as little as it can be we should just strive to go where passions lead us…</p> <h3 id="you-tube-clip-1">You Tube clip</h3> <p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wey8nauEyA4I"><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/Wey8nauEyA4/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Watch the video"/></a></p> <p>Only a couple of years after watching <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dead_Poets_Society">Dead Poets Society</a> another terrific movie come across my watch list… <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good_Will_Hunting">Good Will Hunting</a>. While the movie is all a master piece from the start to the end, I just want to share one of the epic moments in which Robin really gives a wanderful speech that reminded me on the importance of living rather than reading about life. For as many books, stories, quotes, linkedin posts or instagram stories we have watched/listned to, we must live our emotions to the deepest point and we must strive to have our own vision of the world around us, rather then a surrogate version often offered to us.</p> <h3 id="you-tube-clip-2">You Tube clip</h3> <p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8GY3sO47YYo"><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/8GY3sO47YYo/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Watch the video"/></a></p> <p>I hope this post gave you some insights on what type of movies Robin Williams was able to deliver and I want to leave you with one of my favourite quotes from one of his early stand-up comedies…</p> <blockquote> <p>“We are only given a little bit of madness in life … and if we lose that, we are nothing.”</p> </blockquote> <h3 id="you-tube-clip-3">You Tube clip</h3> <p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=klvLQ-lMfrw"><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/klvLQ-lMfrw/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Watch the video"/></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="quotes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[looking forward to summer]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tricks for faster MPC in Casadi</title><link href="https://gregoriomarchesini.github.io/blog/2025/to-function/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tricks for faster MPC in Casadi"/><published>2025-05-04T16:40:16+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-04T16:40:16+00:00</updated><id>https://gregoriomarchesini.github.io/blog/2025/to-function</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gregoriomarchesini.github.io/blog/2025/to-function/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="running-faster-mpc">Running faster MPC</h1> <p>When dealing with nonlinear Model Predicive Control (MPC), there is often a question on how to make the code faster. I will consider the general purpose optimization library <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">casadi</code>.</p> <p>A few main key factors are essential to speed up your solution time.</p> <p>1) <strong>Warm-starting</strong> 2) <strong>Use <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">to_function()</code> to save your mpc controller</strong></p> <p>The process of warm staring consists on letting the solver save the previous solution as the initial guess for the next iteration. Indeed, in problems like MPC, where the same optimization problem is solved repeateadly for many iterations, it is critical to reuse as much computation as possible.</p> <p>On the other hand, the use of the method <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">to_function</code> from <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Opti</code> is always suggested to speed0up your MPC code. We can have a look at an example</p> <div class="jupyter-notebook" style="position: relative; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto;"> <div class="jupyter-notebook-iframe-container"> <iframe src="/assets/jupyter/base_mpc.ipynb.html" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; border-style: none;" width="100%" height="100%" onload="this.parentElement.style.paddingBottom = (this.contentWindow.document.documentElement.scrollHeight + 10) + 'px'"></iframe> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="coding"/><category term="mpc"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[march & april, looking forward to summer]]></summary></entry></feed>